Would you like to take a policy where the insurance
cover of both husband and wife is in a single policy? Would you like to take such an insurance policy where
you need short term income, that is, you get income every year for 101 years?
Would you like to take such a policy where you get income every year for 40 years? Would
you like to take such a policy where you get income every year along with a
maturity benefit? You want to take such an insurance policy where
on death, the death benefit is immediately given to the family members, the insurance of the wife continues and
the income keeps coming, if the wife dies, the death benefit goes to the nominee or
my children, who are my legal heirs, get it and they also keep getting income and
also get maturity benefit, that you want such a policy where you
want to deposit it without taking income every year, you can do that too, where you feel that if I
do not take income, my insurance cover will increase? Do
you want a policy with this type of option? Do you want
to purchase a policy like accidental cover, disabilities cover, cancer cover or any critical illness, then
you can get all these benefits and features. HDFC Life Insurance recently launched a product
called Click to Achieve Par Advantage Plan. This
is a participating plan which will be a bonus or policy for you. So keeping your needs in mind,
many options have been given. In this video, I will explain all of them one
by one in details. If you like the video, then
definitely like, share and subscribe my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS. And if you
want to purchase a participating long term income type policy in this way, then I
will give you the link in the description from where you will also be able to purchase the policy because
in this plan you have been given seven solutions which can confuse you a bit. So
from the beginning itself, I have tried to tell you in a summary that
how these solutions will work in this plan. Here, there
are seven smart students in the solution. Spouse care is For Ever Dream, My Choice Advantage, Family Income
Advantage, Flexible Lumpsum Advantage and Young Ujjwal Bhavishya Advantage.
Seven solutions have been given in it. You have five options out of which three options are already
started - Early Income, Balance Income and Lumpsum Income. In future, you
can also get the option of Ins Income and Guaranteed Income. Here in Early Income, suppose you
are investing lakhs and you have taken solution number one, then 85% of your money will be invested
or the savings will be for Early Income and 15% will go for Balance Income which
will help you in maturity. Will you get the option of Additional Life or not, that is,
can I take Joint Life Insurance cover in that option? So you will see
that it is not available in the first four options, but in Family
Income Advantage, Flex, Lumpsum Advantage and Young Star Ujjwal Bhavishya, you
can also take insurance cover for Joint Life. In which options you
will have to take PCB mandatorily, you cannot remove it optionally, it will be mandatory for you to take it and
in which options you can take it or not, it is optional and in which
PCB is not available at all, in which you will have to take POA mandatorily, paid pension means
where you do not get cash bonus and if you want to increase the insurance cover in front of the bonus,
then you will have to take that option, in which PO option is not available,
in which all these options you have a deferment period available between 0 years to 12 years,
if you want to take deferment period then you can take it, here
you will get death benefit of five times, seven times and 11 times of annual premium,
I will suggest you take 11 times insurance cover so that the income coming on it
is tax free, if the insurance cover is less than 10 times, then
the maturity coming on it is taxable even if your premium is less than 5 lakhs,
but if your insurance cover If it is more than 10 times i.e. 11 times and your
annual premium is Rs. 5 lakh or less, then
the income that comes as maturity or survival benefit is tax free. Here you are
also given the option of pay out in advance. This is not available in Age of Now sales, but if
the company rolls it out in future, then you can also get income in advance in the sense that
if you purchase the policy on 26 June 2025, then the first income will come to you on 26 June 2026. This
is called arrears. Advance means you
get income within seven working days at the time of policy insurance. So this option will not roll out now.
In future there will be eligibility criteria, so here
any person from new born baby to 65 years can purchase this policy. If you
opt for PCB rider, then the minimum age will be 18 years and maximum
person up to 60 years can purchase this policy. Premium payment term: Here you
can buy this policy on single premium. Premium payment options of 5 pay, 6 pay, 8 pay, 10 pay and 12 pay
are available. You can take the policy term from 10 years to 40 years.
You can take the depreciation period from zero to 12 years.
Now let's talk about other benefits and features of this policy which are inbuilt in the policy.
First of all let's look at the option to decrease premium. After 5 years, if you
want to decrease or reduce the annual premium that you are paying in
the policy, you can do it. For example, your annual premium is ₹ lakh and
you have paid five premiums and your premium payment was for 10 years. Now if you feel that I
will not be able to pay ₹ lakh, for any reason I can pay ₹ lakh, then you
can reduce your premium by 50% and pay the remaining five premiums.
The next option is premium offset. Suppose you want to pay the premium from the bonus that you get every year,
then you can pay. For example, if your premium was ₹ lakh,
suppose you were getting ₹ 00 bonus, then from next year when your premium
is to increase, ₹ 00 will be paid from the bonus, the remaining ₹ 70 will remain with you and if
your bonus exceeds ₹ lakh, then you will not be allowed to pay the premium. Let's talk about
deferral of survival benefit. This is an option that you
do not need to take the deferral period like you take in the beginning of the policy. For example, your income
term has started, you have turned 101 years and now you feel that the income that you are getting every year,
now you do not need the income, now you want to save it, want to defer it,
then you can do that. You can defer it and you
will get the growth of the bonus deposited by you as per the RBI bank rate on a per month compounding rate.
Let's talk about special date. If you
want to take the bonus or the income that you are getting every year on a particular date, suppose you
want to take it on the anniversary or on your birthday, then you
can select a particular date also and you will get the income at that time. Let's talk about death benefit in
installment. If you die and you don't want to take the lump sum benefit, and the nominee
wants to take it as income every month or every year for between 5 to 15 years, then
he can select this option. Paid up addition. If you
want to increase the insurance cover in front of the bonus, then you can select the option of paid up addition. Special
milestone benefit here, if you select this option, then
you can get up to 50% of the total premium that you would have paid on a special day or a special milestone
day. If you want to take this money, you can take it,
50% of the total premium that you have paid. Now I am going to explain to you in the next slide
what will be the death benefit in all the solutions of this policy, what will be the survival benefit,
what will be the maturity benefit, how will PCB work, in which
option is the option of POA available, so you will understand all these benefits and features.
In the benefit illustration, the company has not enrolled the age of now for waiver of premium. As far as
I searched, I am not getting the option of waiver and premium there.
In future, you will also get the option of waiver premium, but it is already of PCB, it
works like a type of waiver, the increase in premium is waived. That
benefit is immediately available, income continues and maturity is also available, plus
separate waiver and premium, like if there is any accidental incident, disability,
critical illness, then the option of paying premium there will be internalized in future,
you will get it. So let us understand
all these benefits from the benefit illustration - death benefit, survival benefit, maturity benefit, PU and
PCB. Now let us understand all the options of this policy from the benefit illustration.
So the name of the plan is HDFC Life Click to Power Advantage Plan, where a 35-year-old
person who is purchasing the policy will pay the premium for 10 years,
the policy term will be 40 years, let us assume he pays an annual premium of ₹5 lakh and the
solution he selects is Smart Student Advantage,
where the option taken in the plan is the early income option, and balance
income options will be available at the age of now. Only these two options are visible in all these solutions.
Only one lump sum is visible, out of the remaining five, you will see these three options, two
are this and the third is lump sum where the premium payment term is selected for 10 years,
the policy term is 40 years, the deferment period is selected as 0 years and here 85% of
the money will go into early income, ₹75,000,
the remaining 15% will go into balance income for you. The death benefit insurance
cover has been purchased 11 times the sum matured and maturity. By combining these two,
the guaranteed amount that you finally see at maturity is ₹553,000,
you will get this from here, plus you will also get bonus based maturity, by adding this,
the insurance cover will be ₹55 lakh from the first day and the income that you will get in the first year
will come on 26 June 2026. If you purchase the policy on 26 June 2025, your additional life option
is not available in this option, PCB is mandatory for you. In this option, you will have to take
premium offset. If you want to get it done, you can select paid up addition.
No special date is available in this option. If you want to select
in future, you can do it in future. If you want to select in future, you can do it.
Annual premium of ₹5 lakh in the first year with GST, you have to pay ₹5,22,500.
4.5% GST will be applicable and from next year your GST will be ₹.5%, so
your premium will be ₹5,11,250. Now from here, let us understand that
the customer has paid this premium of 5 lakh for 10 years. In this column, you
will see guaranteed benefit. This will be of non-guaranteed 4%. A column of non-guaranteed 8% will be visible. In this
column, you will see maturity benefit, which will be seen at 4%, one
at 8% and one in death benefit, you can see in the column of 4% and one death
benefit You can see it in the column of 8% and if you want to see the surrender benefit also, then
what is the surrender benefit on the growth of 4% of the surrender benefit and what
is the surrender benefit on 8% of 8%, what is the surrender benefit on 4%, you can also see that here,
now when you pay the premium in June 2025, you will start getting income from June 2026,
you will get income of Rs 1,87,375 for the next 40 years, this
bonus based income will come to you, if you want to reinvest this income somewhere,
you can do that as well and along with this you will get a maturity benefit,
if you want 8%, then you will get a maturity of ₹93.64 lakh and if you want 4%, then
you will get a maturity benefit of ₹92.35 lakh,
this ₹55,000 is also added in the maturity benefit, if you add it here, you will see
at 8%, Column number six, column number 15 and terminal bonus, by combining these three you
get maturity. Terminal bonus is declared by the company at the end of the policy. So
by combining these three you get the final maturity.
What will be the insurance cover from day one? ₹55 lakhs. It is not seen increasing a bit in the future.
So your insurance cover will be ₹55 lakhs through the policy term. If you
want to surrender the policy at any time, then you can also see the surrender benefit here
that how much money you will get on surrender. I have
explained this option in detail so that you can understand all the other options easily. Now let's talk about the second
option, which is the solution of spouse care advantage. There are no changes, everything remains
the same. ₹25 lakhs will go to early income. ₹75000 your balance will go to income.
You will get maturity. There are no additional options. PCB will be mandatory. There will be an insurance of ₹55
lakhs. When will the income start coming? What will be the premium for you?
Take surrender benefit, everything will remain same, maturity benefit will also remain same.
Option number three, solution number three, forever dream advantage
will remain same, nothing is changed, everything is going to remain same. Here also you
will not see any difference, you will see same maturity, so whichever of the first three
options you want to select, the solution does not matter,
you will see the same benefits and features.
Now let's see solution number four, by taking my choice advantage, you will see here you will
see a little more income, ₹ 195,000 income is visible, plus you
will also see a little more maturity, ₹ 845,
why is this more visible to you, ₹ 1000, because in this option you
do not get PCB rider, you do not get policy continuation benefit. Policy continuation benefit
means that for example, this option is selected, for example
and Where the policy continuation benefit is yes, let us assume that the customer
has paid two premiums and the customer dies, then the nominee
gets the insurance cover of Rs. 55 lakhs immediately and the company itself will pay the remaining eight premiums, the customer does not have to pay.
The income of ₹1,87,000 that was coming will continue to come to the nominees and
the ₹93 lakh that was to go on maturity will also come, so this is called PCB
rider. So, in the M Choice solution, PCB rider is not available because it
is not available, due to this, you will get a little more income here, more maturity
will come. Now, for example, suppose here, a customer who has paid five premiums dies, he
will get ₹55 lakh, the policy will be closed, this income will not continue, neither will maturity come.
Now, let's see the next option, which is called Family Income Advantage Option.
I have told you your early income and percentage in the Family Income Advantage Option.
Here, you will also get Additional Life Option. Here, you will see the option, Additional Life
Option is also written as Yes and PCB is also Yes. Both of these
are mandatory for you to take. Now, for example, you can see here that a premium of ₹5 lakh
is being paid. Suppose you pay two premiums
here because now the spouse also has insurance cover of ₹55 lakhs, so now
your income will not be ₹175000, it will be ₹
187, it will not be ₹195 because now if you look at the insurance cover, if you look at the death benefit
column , you will see the
insurance cover of both Life Insurance One and Life Insurance Two
of ₹55 lakhs and you have also taken PCB benefit and suppose after two premiums the husband dies, for example, the wife gets ₹55 lakhs,
okay, the remaining premiums are waived off, eight premiums and this income of ₹175000
is going to the wife, now unfortunately let us assume that after 20 years the wife dies,
then the wife's ₹55 lakhs will now be given to her children who are legal heirs and the income
will continue ₹175000 to their legal highs and the ₹87
lakhs that you are going to get on maturity will also come.
Now let's see
the next option which is called
Flexible Lumpsum Advantage Taxable Lumpsum Advantage,
here you neither have to take additional life option nor policy continuation benefit,
so now
the option that you will get here is paid pension, paid pension is yes, that means
now the bonus that you are getting, you are not taking it every year, you are depositing it in the company,
it is automatically, so this insurance is being purchased by you, it
will keep getting accumulated continuously and this option I will tell you again, this is a lumpsum option, that means here
income will come every year, you get lumpsum money together in the policy, so how much
money are you getting in lumpsum 4 crore 3684000
and here if you also see the insurance cover, then you will see it in increasing order
because you are not withdrawing money every year, so you can deposit it, but if In
between, if you ever need it in the future, there is an addition on the cash value of accrued,
you can cash it out, if you want to withdraw it, you can withdraw it, it
is not that you will get the bonus in the 40th year, if you want to withdraw it in between, you can withdraw it,
so in these options, there is a lump sum option where you
can take the additional life option or you can not, it depends on your choice, whether you want to take it, add it
or not, if you do not add it, then your maturity will be up to ₹4 crore 36 lakhs,
if you add it, then the maturity will be a little less, like
you took this flexible lump sum advantage option, but this time you
have also said yes to the additional life option and have also said yes to policy continuation, so now your 4 crore maturity
will not come, now your maturity will be 398714
and you will see the insurance cover of both your husband and wife here
of 555 lakhs and you have already got the benefit of PCB Let us understand that there is a death, suppose
after paying two premiums, the death occurs, the company will itself pay the remaining premiums, the first insurance
cover will be given to the nominee and later if the wife also dies, the rest of
the insurance cover will also be given to the family and the maturity that is to come will definitely
come, so in this way you can see whether you want to take lump sum income or
take pension by accumulating it, keep increasing the insurance cover or you want
to take early income every year, I am taking all these options of 40 years income term, you can take income term 10 years, 15
years, 20 years in this way as per your need, if you want then you can take it, now
the next option is Young Star Ujjwal Bhavishya Advantage, it
is the same as you have seen in the last option, here you
will get additional life option, you will also get PCB benefit and here the income that you are going to get,
₹1,75,000, will come, on maturity you were getting ₹87 lakhs, the same will come Nothing will change,
you will see the same options, I will tell you a final solution where if
If the customer wants to take deferred income, suppose he
has taken the first option Smart Student and he has selected the deferred period there,
then how will he get income, suppose the deferred period is 12 years, then he
will not get income immediately, here he will get income after 12 years, how much will he get? 4396,
39, 40 years of age and here the maturity will also
be 1 crore 58 lakhs, so now according to your requirement, you
want to take the income from the first year, from the fifth year or after the 12th year, it is up to you that
from when do you want to start the income, there
is a small concern which I
want to ask the people who designed the product of HDFC Life Insurance, suppose in this plan,
if the customer selects the session by taking My Choice Advantage and here he
is not taking any additional option, then the maturity shown to him at 4% and 8%
is from 4% to 1 crore ₹127199 from 8% to 9845000
So how are 1 crore at 4% and 98 lakhs at 8%? Please explain a little bit
that since when did the maturity at 4% start becoming higher than 8%? Please
do explain and write in the comment box. Thank you so much. Now you have seen the benefit illustration,
but I will summarize it for you so that you can understand it easily.
For example, the customer's age is 35 years, the wife's age is also 35 years , they pay premium
for 10 years, the annual premium is ₹5 lakh, the premium payment term is 10 years
, the policy term is 40 years and after selecting all the seven options, the first three options are as it
is the same, there is no difference, Smart Student, Spouse Care and Forever Dream,
all three are the same. The fourth option which is My Choice Advantage is also similar to the first three,
but there is only one thing in it that whatever you You don't have to take the PCB one as a mandatory option.
In the rest of the first three options, PCB is mandatory. The fifth option for you is
Flexible Lumpsum Advantage and the seventh option is Young Star Ujjwal Bhavishya Advantage.
Both of these are similar. In both of these, you get additional life cover as well as PCB
benefit. And the third one will be unique for you in a way, the Flexible Lumpsum
Advantage one. If you want to take PCB rider and additional life cover,
you can take it. If you don't want to, you can also not take it as an option. So it will come separately.
Now let's see, if you purchase Smart Student Advantage policy and
pay a premium of Rs. 5 lakh, then how much income will you get? ₹187375.
The maturity will be ₹93.64 lakh and the insurance cover will be ₹55 lakh from the first day.
All these three are going to be the same in the first three options. In the fourth option, you
will get 195 instead of 187 because you have not taken PCB rider. In the fifth
option, you will see that your income has reduced from 187 to 175 because now you
have also taken insurance cover for spouse cover, which means that wife
is also getting insurance cover and in the fifth and seventh option, in the sixth, fifth and seventh option, in Family
Income Advantage in Young Star, you are getting the same income of 175 and
your spouse cover is also getting insured but in the sixth and seventh option,
in the Flexible Lumpsum Advantage feature, you will get lumpsum income where there
is an income of 4.36 CR and there is a cover of 55 lakhs from the first day but if you take PCB as well and
add spouse cover, then your maturity will become 3.91 CR and
the insurance cover of ₹50 lakh of spouse will also be added. So from here you
can summarize and see where the income will be more and where how much less income will come on taking PCB rider
or how much more insurance cover will be additional when you take PCB for wife or for spouse.
If you add insurance cover, what will be the difference in income? Now from here you
can easily understand which solution you have to select according to your need.
In this, you will get loan up to 80% loan is available. Surrender benefit and RPO benefits
are also available in this policy. Tax benefit is still
available in the income tax section ATC. If you want to take the benefit of ATC according to new grid and old grid in tax, then it
is still available up to ₹ 1.5 lakh, but
more important than ATC is for big people 1010D where you get the upcoming income or
maturity tax free, then these options are also available. If your annual premium
is less than 5 lakhs and insurance cover is at least 10 times, in this policy you
will also get a grace period of 30 days. The free look period is also of 30 days. The revival period
in this will be of 5 years. Riders are also given in the policy, in which
in case of an accident, you will get 1% of that rider every month. If you want to take it for the next 10 years
So you can add this rider which is called HDFC Life Income Benefit on Accidental
Disabilities Rider. If you want to add cancer cover or accidental death and disability rider,
then you can add HDFC L Protect Plus rider. And if you
want to add 60 critical illness benefit, then you can take HDFC L Health Plus rider. You
can also take waiver premium rider when you enroll in future. Finally,
if I summarize it, then this is an excellent plan which has been made keeping in
mind your many needs. You want to take short term or long term income, you want to take cash bonus, you
want to accumulate cash bonus, you want to increase insurance cover as PO, you
want to take PCB rider or not, you want to add spouse cover, you want to take
waiver of premium, there is critical illness, there is disabilities cover,
you get income every year in case of an accident, you are getting milestone benefit. Along with this, if you
want to take income on your special date, then you are getting that.
You have also been given many options for premium payment and a good This is the policy of the brand, but this policy
is a participating policy, it is a bonus based policy, every year the company declares the bonus,
accordingly you get income, this bonus can be more or less in the future, this
is also a thing worth keeping in mind, so if you want to purchase a participating policy
of HDFC or any other company, then a link has been given in the description,
through that you can also purchase a participating policy, if you liked the video then before
leaving do not forget to subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajput Triple FS
where you will find more than 300 videos related to insurance which
will help you a lot in insurance related financial planning, thank you so much, Jai Hind